Farhan Salam

H. 371, St. 122 G-9/3, Islamabad

0333 5116667

farhan.salam@hotmail.com

SUMMARY

Professional with 2+ years of combined experience in Backend Web Services Development, Node JS web development, Various Forms of Database Structuring and Queries, RESTful API development and Server management. Currently responsible for (but not limited to) Data analysis of a Social Business platform based in California , as well as recruiting process management at Red buffer, Islamabad.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer, Red Buffer

Islamabad — October 2013 - Till Present

Red Buffer is a services based Web and Mobile Development Startup. I provide Web applications development expertise to the startup, while actively co-operate with fellow team members working on backend web services, front end and server management.

Accomplishments

- Backend Web Services Development in PHP Laravel and CodeIgniter Frameworks.
- Backend Web Services Development in Ruby on Rails
- NodeJS Web Application development
- REST API Development
- Front End development in HTML/HAML, with Javascript using JQuery, AngularJS and Bootstrap.
- Scripts Development in Bash, PHP and Ruby(Sinatra)
- Implementation of Web Application Analytics using services like Segment, Mixpanel, Intercom and ChartIO.
- MySQL Database structuring, Scripts and Query writing.
- PSQL Database Queries and Structuring.
- MongoDB used with NodeJS
- Server installation and Deployments of Apps. Servers I worked with are Nginx and Redis
- Working back and forth between Growth, engagement and development teams deployed in Pakistan and California.

Software Engineer, Easy Ad Software Development

Islamabad — July 2013 - September 2013

EasyAd was an Ad Serving Agency, providing Internet ads through their own servers. I was responsible for design and Develop backend and frontend of their web application which was built in **PHP (Kohana).**

Accomplishments

- Developed backend Services in PHP
- Front End templates using HTML CSS.
- Front End functionalities using JQuery and core javascript
- OpenX Plugin Development

Intern, NADRA

Islamabad — January 2013 - March 2013

Worked as an intern at **NADRA SND Department**, which was providing it's services to a reputable government institution. It was a great learning experience.

Accomplishments

- Learned about the process and requirement gathering for a Web Project
- Basic work on backend and frontend of a web application.
- Gathered extensive knowledge about Oracle DB

Intern, LMKT

Islamabad -- Oct 2012 - Dec 2012

LMKT is a product based Software Development firm. I have worked there as an intern in VGovern Team.

Accomplishments

- Understanding workflows of an organization
- Requirements and Testing of a product
- Development of team procedures

EDUCATION

College of Electrical and Mechanical Engineering, NUST

B.E. Electrical Engineering — 2008-2012

Islamabad College for Boys, G-6/3

HSSC Pre Engineering — 2006-2008

Islamabad College for Boys, G-6/3

SSC Science — 2004-2006

SKILLS

- Vast knowledge of Web Application Structure
- Backend Services (REST API) Development
- Web Application Front End designing and development
- Data Analytics of a web application
- Database Structuring and query writing (MYSQL, PSQL and MongoDB)
- Server Management (NGINX, Redis)
- Programming Languages with strong grip on PHP, NodeJS, Javascript and Ruby

INTERESTS

- I am a tech enthusiast, latest technologies and gadgets excite me.
- Sports and E-Gaming.
- Travelling to Northern areas of Pakistan.

REFERENCES

Available upon request.